<HelpWanted>
	<Topic name="New Class Wizard">Maintain or write a new New Class wizard (see new <pre>src\AddIns\Wizards\NewClassWizard</pre> and new file dialog)</Topic>
	<Topic name="Pretty Printer">Finish the pretty printer (see SharpRefactory in <pre>src\Libraries\SharpRefactory</pre>)</Topic>
	<Topic name="Optimize addin-tree loading speed">Currently XML DOM is used to load the addin tree but using the XmlTextReader directly would speed up the loading if you want to take this job see the Core in <pre>src\Main\Core</pre>)</Topic>
	<Topic name="Optimize project loading speed">Currently XML DOM is used to load the projects and combines but using the XmlTextReader directly would speed up the loading if you want to take this job see the Base project in <pre>src\Main\Base</pre> (especially <pre>Internal\Project</pre>)</Topic>
	<Topic name="Debugger">Help us with the debugger. We have started a debbug but we need help. C++ skills are required. For a debugger example look in the <pre>Microsoft.NET/SDK/v1.1/Tool Developers Guide/Samples/debugger</pre> directory. But don't take ANY code from there (licensing problems).</Topic>
	<Topic name="Subversion plugin"><a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/">Subversion</a> is a version control system that is used for the #develop development. But we need a plugin for that. Don't wrap the command line client instead use the subversion libraries. There is already a project for Visual Studio.NET called <a href="http://ankhsvn.tigris.org/">Ankh</a> you should take their NSvn sources. The Ankh plugin and the underlying Subversion interop sources should be a good starting point.</Topic>
	<Topic name="Project Converter">Write a C# Builder project converter. You can plug in into the project converter infrastructure. (see <pre>src\AddIns\Misc\ProjectImporterExporter</pre>)</Topic>
	<Topic name="Backend Bindings">Maintain the Java backend binding</Topic>

	<Topic name="Translation">Help to translate #D contact <a href="mailto:christophw@alphasierrapapa.com">Christoph Wille, christophw@alphasierrapapa.com</a> regarding this issue (even report spelling errors)</Topic>
	<Topic name="ReportBugs">If you find bugs report them to <a href="mailto:mike@icsharpcode.net">Mike Krueger, mike@icsharpcode.net</a> try to report the same bug again and again this increases the chance that it gets done sooner</Topic>
</HelpWanted>
